Let's now look at things on the decoder side.
现在我们来看看解码器部分
In models without attention,
在不具有注意力机制的模型中
we'd only feed the last context vector to the decoder RNN,
除了结束标记的嵌入之外
in addition to the embedding of the end token,
我们仅将最后一个语境向量馈送给解码器 RNN
and it will begin to generate an element of the output sequence at each time-step.
它将开始在每个时间步生成输出序列的一个元素
The case is different in an attention decoder, however.
但是具有注意力机制的解码器有所不同
An attention decoder has the ability to look at the inputted words,
注意力解码器能够查看输入的单词
and the decoders own hidden state,
以及解码器自己的隐藏状态
and then it would do the following.
然后执行以下操作
It would use a scoring function to score each hidden state in the context matrix.
它将使用一个评分函数对语境矩阵中的每个隐藏状态评分
We'll talk later about the scoring function,
稍后我们将讲解评分函数
but after scoring each context vector would end up with
每次评分之后 每个语境向量就生成一个得分
a certain score and if we feed these scores into a softmax function,
如果我们将这些得分馈送给一个 softmax 函数
we end up with scores that are all positive,
就会获得全为正数的得分
that are all between zero and one,
全在 0 和 1 之间
and that all sum up to one.
并且所有数值之和为 1
These values are how much each vector will be expressed in
这些值表示每个向量在注意力向量中的表示程度
the attention vector that the decoder will look at before producing an output.
并且解码器在生成输出之前会查看这些注意力向量
Simply multiplying each vector by its softmax score and then,
只需将每个向量与其 softmax 得分相乘
summing up these vectors produces an attention contexts vector,
然后将这些向量相加 得出注意力语境向量
this is a basic weighted sum operation.
这是一种基本加权和运算
The context vector is an important milestone in this process,
语境向量是这个流程的重要组成部分
but it's not the end goal.
但并不是最终目标
In a later video, we'll explain how the context vector merges with
在下个视频中 我们将了解语境向量
the decoders hidden state to create the real output of the decoder at the time-step.
如何与解码器隐藏状态合并 在时间步创建解码器的真实输出
The decoder has now looked at the input word and at the attention context vector,
解码器现在查看了输入单词和注意力语境向量
which focused its attention on the appropriate place in the input sequence.
而注意力语境向量集中查看的是输入序列的相应位置
So, it produces a hidden state and it produces the first word in the output sequence.
它输出隐藏状态并生成输出序列的第一个单词
Now, this is still an over-simplified look,
这依然是过于简化的图形
that's why we have the asterisks here.
因此在这里添加了星号
There is still a step,
在 RNN 和最终输出之间
whether we'll talk about in later video,
依然有一个步骤
between the RNN and the final output.
我们将在下个视频中讨论
In the next time-step,
在下个时间步
the RNN takes its previous output as an input,
RNN 将之前的输出作为输入
and it generates its own context vector for that time-step,
为该时间步生成自己的语境向量
as well as the hidden state from the previous time-step,
以及上个时间步的隐藏状态
and that produces new hidden state for the decoder,
并为解码器生成新的隐藏状态
and a new word in the output sequence,
以及输出序列中的新单词
and this goes on until we've completed our output sequence.
一直持续下去 直到完成输出序列